[
  {
    "question": "Q. Abraham’s call",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 12"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. All in Adam",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Armor of God",
    "answer": "A. Eph. 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Ascension of Christ",
    "answer": "A. Mark 16; Luke 24; Acts 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Baptism",
    "answer": "A. Matt 28; Acts 2, 16; 1 Cor. 10; Col. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Biblical Discipline",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 18; 1 Cor. 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Superiority",
    "answer": "A. Heb. 1-3, 7-8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Humanity",
    "answer": "A. Luke 2 – virgin birth;<br>Phil. 2 – 'taking the form of a servant';<br>Col. 2 – 'for in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily';<br>Heb. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Humiliation",
    "answer": "A. Phil. 2 – 'being found in human form he humbled himself by becoming obedient to the point of death';<br>Heb. 2 – 'for a little while was made lower than the angels"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Priesthood",
    "answer": "A. Hebrews 4, 5, 7, 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Resurrection",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 28; Mark 16; Luke 24; John 20; 1 Cor. 15"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Return",
    "answer": "A. 1 Thess. 4-5; Matt. 24-25"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christ’s Temptation",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 4; Mark 1; Luke 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Christian liberty",
    "answer": "A. 1 Cor. 8-10; Rom. 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Church (As Christ’s body)",
    "answer": "A. 1 Cor. 12; Eph. 4-5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Church (Attendance)",
    "answer": "A. Heb. 10 – 'not neglecting to meet together';<br>Acts 2 – devoted themselves to...<br>Rom. 10 – 'faith comes by hearing';<br>Rom. 12 & 1 Cor. 12 – 'members of the same body';<br>Eph. 4; James 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Civil Government",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 22 & Luke 20 – render to Caesar;<br>Rom. 13 – 'be subject to the governing authorities';<br>1 Peter 2 – 'be subject to every human institution'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Command to Keep Law",
    "answer": "A. John 14; Matt. 5; Deut. 11, 16"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant blessings/curses",
    "answer": "A. Deut. 28"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant of Redemption",
    "answer": "A. Ps. 2, 110; Luke 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant of Works",
    "answer": "A. Gen 2-3;<br>Hos. 6 – 'Like Adam they transgressed the covenant'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant of Grace",
    "answer": "A. Jer. 31-32; Ezek. 34; Heb. 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant with Abraham",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 12, 15, 17"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Covenant with Solomon",
    "answer": "A. 1 Kings 9; 2 Chr. 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. David’s Confession",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 51"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Davidic Covenant",
    "answer": "A. 2 Sam. 7; 1 Chr. 7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Day of Atonement",
    "answer": "A. Lev. 16"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Death of Christ (event)",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 27; Mark 15; Luke 23; John 19"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Deity of Christ",
    "answer": "A. John 1, 10; Phil. 2; Col. 1-2; Heb. 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Elijah on Mount Carmel (prophets of Baal)",
    "answer": "A. 1 Kings 18"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Emmaus Road",
    "answer": "A. Luke 24"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Faith and Works",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 2; Titus 3; James 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Flesh versus Spirit",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 7; Gal. 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Great Commission",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 28; Mark 16; Luke 24; John 21; Acts 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. High Priestly Prayer",
    "answer": "A. John 17"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Husbands and Wives",
    "answer": "A. Eph. 5; 1 Peter 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the bread of life",
    "answer": "A. John 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the light of the world",
    "answer": "A. John 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the sheep gate",
    "answer": "A. John 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the good shepherd",
    "answer": "A. John 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the resurrection and the life",
    "answer": "A. John 11"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the way, the truth, and the life",
    "answer": "A. John 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. I Am the true vine",
    "answer": "A. John 15"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Imitate Christ’s example",
    "answer": "A. Phil. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Irrestible Grace",
    "answer": "A. John 6 – The Father draws;<br>Rom. 8 – 'And those whom he predestined he also called';<br>Eph. 2 – We were once dead in our trespasses"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Jerusalem Council",
    "answer": "A. Acts 15"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Justification by Grace thru faith",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 1-5; Gal. 1-5; Eph. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Law Summarized",
    "answer": "A. Lev. 19; Deut. 6, 11; Matt. 22; Mark 12, Luke 10"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Law and Grace",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 3; Gal. 3"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Limited Atonement",
    "answer": "A. John 6 – 'No one can come to Me unless the Father who sent Me draws him';<br>John 10 – 'I am the good shepherd. I know my own and my own know me...'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Lord’s Prayer",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 6; Luke 11"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Lord’s Supper",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 26; Mark 14; Luke 22; John 13; 1 Cor. 11"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Millennium",
    "answer": "A. Rev. 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Nebuchadnezzar’s Dreams",
    "answer": "A. Dan. 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Necessity of Faith",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 3 – propitiation received by faith;<br>Heb. 11 – without faith it is impossible to please him"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Necessity of Repentance",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 6 – Two masters;<br>Matt. 7 – Sin leads to death, obedience to life;<br>Rom. 6 – old self is crucified;<br>Heb. 10 – Remaining in Sin;<br>Luke 24 – repentance should be proclaimed;<br>Acts 2, 3, 17;<br>Mark 13 – Always be Prepared;<br>John 3 – Only Believers;<br>Joel 2/1 John 1 – God Will Forgive the Repentant"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. New Covenant",
    "answer": "A. Jer. 31; Ezek. 36; Heb. 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. New Heaven and New Earth",
    "answer": "A. Rev. 21-22"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Old Man/New Man",
    "answer": "A. Rom 7; Eph. 4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Olivet Discourse",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 24-25; Mark 13; Luke 21"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Parables of the Kingdom",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 13; Mark 4; Luke 13"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Paul’s Conversion",
    "answer": "A. Acts 9 (repeated Acts 22, 26)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Paul’s Areopagus Sermon",
    "answer": "A. Acts 17"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Perseverance of the Saints",
    "answer": "A. John 10 – 'No one will snatch them out of my hand';<br>Phil. 1 – 'He who began'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Peter’s Confession",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 16; Mark 8; Luke 9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Predestination",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 11; Rom. 8-11; Eph. 1, 11; 1 Peter 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Prophecies of Christ",
    "answer": "A. Isaiah 9; 53; Micah 5; Gen. 3; 2 Sam. 22; Psalm 18"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Qualifications for church officers",
    "answer": "A. 1 Tim. 3; Titus 1; Acts 6-8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Resurrection of Christ (event)",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 28; Mark 16; Luke 24; John 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Resurrection of the Body",
    "answer": "A. 1 Cor. 15; 1 Thess. 4; Rev. 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Revelation of God in nature",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 1; Psalm 19"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Sacraments as Means of Grace",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 4 – Abraham acting in faith;<br>Rom. 6;<br>1 Cor. 10;<br>1 Cor. 11 – The Lord's Supper <strong>proclaims</strong>"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Sanctification",
    "answer": "A. Rom. 6-8; Eph. 4; 1 John"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Scripture",
    "answer": "A. Psalm 19, 119; 2 Tim. 3; 2 Peter 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Second coming of Christ",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 24; 1 Thess. 4-5; Rev. 22"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Sermon on the Mount",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 5-8; Luke 6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Sexual Impurity",
    "answer": "A. John 8; Rom. 1; 1 Cor. 6; 2 Peter 2; Jude 8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Ten Commandments",
    "answer": "A. Ex. 20; Deut. 5"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Healing Miracles",
    "answer": "A. Mark 5 – Heals bleeding woman;<br>John 5 – Jesus heals man by the pool;<br>John 11 – Resurrects Lazarus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Nature Miracles",
    "answer": "A. Mark 4 – Calms the storm;<br>John 2 – Wedding at Cana;<br>Matt. 14 – Feeds 5,000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Miracles in Matthew",
    "answer": "A. Matthew 8 – Calms the storm;<br>Matthew 14 – Feeds 5,000 and walks on water;<br>Matthew 15 – Canaanite Woman"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Miracles in Mark",
    "answer": "A. Mark 2 – Heals a Paralytic;<br>Mark 4 – Calms the storm;<br>Mark 5 – Heals woman bleeding/Jarius daughter;<br>Mark 6 – Feeds 5,000 and walks on water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Miracles in Luke",
    "answer": "A. Luke 8 – Calms the storm;<br>Luke 8 – Heals Jarius Daughter;<br>Luke 9 – Feeds 5,000"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Miracles in John",
    "answer": "A. John 2 – Wedding at Cana;<br>John 5 – Healing at the Pool;<br>John 11 – Resurrection of Lazarus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Parables",
    "answer": "A. Parable of the Sower – Matt. 13, Mark 4, Luke 8;<br>Parable of the Mustard Seed – Matt. 13, Mark 4, Luke 13;<br>Parable of the Tenants – Matt. 21, Mark 12, Luke 20"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Parables only in Luke",
    "answer": "A. Luke 10 – Good Samaritan;<br>Luke 12 – Parable of the Rich Fool<br>Luke 15 – Parable of the Prodigal Son;<br>Luke 16 – Parable of the Rich Man and Lazarus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Three Uses of the Law",
    "answer": "A. (1) Law as mirror (schoolmaster/teacher) — Gal. 3<br>(2) Law restraining evil — 2 Thess. 2<br>(3) Law as guide — John 14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Total Depravity",
    "answer": "A. Gen 6. – 'every intention of the thoughts of his heart was only evil continually';<br>Rom.3 – 'None is righteous, no, not one';<br>Rom. 14 – 'For whatever does not proceed from faith is sin'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Transfiguration of Jesus",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 17; Mark 9; Luke 9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Trinity (Triune God)",
    "answer": "A. Gen. 1; Is. 48; Matt. 3, 28; John 17; 2 Cor. 13; Eph. 1; 1 Peter 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Triumphal Entry into Jerusalem",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 21; Mark 11; Luke 19; John 12"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Two Great Commandments",
    "answer": "A. Matt. 22; Mark 12"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Unconditional Election",
    "answer": "A. Is. 64 – 'all our righteous deeds are like a polluted garment';<br>John 15 – 'You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you';<br>Rom 3 – No one is righteous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Upper Room Discourse",
    "answer": "A. John 13-14"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. Virgin Birth",
    "answer": "A. Isaiah 7; Matt. 1; Luke 1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the Covenant of Redemption including scripture references?",
    "answer": "A. The Covenant of Redemption is the theological description of the agreement between God the Father and God the Son to provide for the salvation of sinful humanity by Christ’s death on the cross. WSC 20 states that God, out of His mere good pleasure, from all eternity, elected some to everlasting life, and entered into a covenant of grace to deliver them from sin and misery, bringing them into salvation by a Redeemer. WLC 31 states that the covenant of grace was made with Christ as the second Adam, and in Him with all the elect as His seed.<br>Scripture references include: Ps. 2; 110; Rom. 3:25; 1 Jn. 2:2; Luke 2:49; Eph. 1."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the Covenant of Works including scripture references?",
    "answer": "A. The Covenant of Works is the covenant entered into at creation between man and God. A perfect relationship with God could be enjoyed if humans maintained perfect obedience to God’s law. The parties are God and Adam as the representative of all mankind. WCF 7.2 states that the first covenant made with man was a covenant of works, wherein life was promised to Adam, and in him to his posterity, upon condition of perfect and personal obedience. WSC 12 states that when God had created man, He entered into a covenant of life with him, upon condition of perfect obedience; forbidding him to eat of the tree of the knowledge of good and evil, upon the pain of death.<br>Scripture references include: Gen. 2:17; 3:15; Hos. 6:7; Jer. 33:20-21; Rom. 5:12-19."
  },
  {
    "question": "Q. What is the Covenant of Grace with Scripture references?",
    "answer": "A. The relationship into which God entered to provide, by grace, the promise of salvation and eternal life to sinful humanity. It extends throughout the Old Testament by means of various covenants to its final fulfillment in Christ. God promises to be a God to us and our offspring, mankind is to respond by saving faith in Jesus Christ. Scripture references include Jer. 31-32; Ezek. 34, 36-37; 2 Cor. 6; Heb. 8"
  }
]
